Inventory of the Coleman Wilson Papers 1775-1989, 1919-1964
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Letters, 1919-1967. (Box 1-5)
  - Letters, 1950., 27 items. (Box-folder 3:20-21)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman], wife of George P. Coleman, to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, wife of James Southall Wilson, mainly concerning the activities of their families, August - December 1950., 13 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 3:21)
  - Letters, 1951., 40 items. (Box-folder 3:22-24)
    Singleton Moorehead has hernia operation, opening of Kings Arms Tavern "which is to take the place of the Travis House," demotion of Gen. MacArthur and way people treated him, Cynthia Kimbrough graduates from St. Catherine's, Francis Bland Saunders marries Dick Tyree, building of the Coleman Bridge, Wilson's move, Mr. Rockefeller remarries, Cynthia Kimbrough goes to William and Mary, William and Mary President Pomfret resigns and is replaced by President Chandler, 25th anniversary of the Restoration, Catherine Hubbard born.
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, January - April 1951., 13 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 3:22)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, May - August 1951., 13 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 3:23)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman], wife of George P. Coleman, to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, wife of James Southall Wilson, mainly concerning the activities of their families, September - December 1951., 14 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 3:24)
  - Letters, 1952., 34 items. (Box-folder 4:1-3)
    Ascension of Queen Elizabeth II after King's death, opening of Coleman Bridge, Janet, "Kippy" and Cynthia Kimbrough go to Europe, Janet Kimbrough begins to work at Ft. Eustis, Eisenhower's election, Singleton Moorehead's mother dies.
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, January - April 1952., 11 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:1)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, May - August 1952., 14 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:2)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman], wife of George P. Coleman, to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, wife of James Southall Wilson, mainly concerning the activities of their families, September - December 1952., 9 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Letters, 1953., 38 items. (Box-folder 4:4-6)
    "Kippy" Kimbrough graduates and receives Fulbright scholarship, Adah Begg [Mary Coleman's sister-in-law] dies suddenly, "Kippy" Kimbrough leaves for Europe, Julia and James Wilson go to Davidson.
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, January - April 1953., 11 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:4)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, May - August 1953., 15 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:5)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman], wife of George P. Coleman, to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, wife of James Southall Wilson, mainly concerning the activities of their families, September - December 1953., 12 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Letters, 1954., 32 items. (Box-folder 4:7-9)
    "Kippy" Kimbrough decides to remain in Germany an extra year, Mrs. W.A.R. Goodwin's death, UVA establishes the James Southall Wilson scholarship, reaction to Brown v. Board of Education of Topeka - "this ruling against segregation is in the back of everyone's head just now, and yet everyone is extremely silent on the subject," Tucker Coleman dies, Queen Elizabeth visits Williamsburg.
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, February - April 1954., 9 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:7)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, May - August 1954., 13 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:8)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman], wife of George P. Coleman, to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, wife of James Southall Wilson, mainly concerning the activities of their families, September - December 1954., 10 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:9)
  - Letters, 1955., 44 items. (Box-folder 4:10-12)
    William and Mary incident (fatal automobile accident following fraternity party) - Mary Coleman comments on Alvin Chandler's inability to handle the situation, Cynthia Kimbrough apple blossom princess, Mary Coleman and Julia Wilson go to Colorado to visit Tucker relatives, Cynthia Kimbrough marries Robert Barlowe, Isabelle Hubbard has cataract operation, Wilsons buy a television.
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, January - April 1955., 15 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:10)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, May - August 1955., 16 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:11)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman], wife of George P. Coleman, to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, wife of James Southall Wilson, mainly concerning the activities of their families, September - December 1955., 13 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Letters, 1956., 39 items. (Box-folder 4:13-15)
    James Wilson's sister [Georgie?] dies, Alida Davison has ectopic pregnancy, Tucker House gets a washing machine, Frank Craighill leaves Bruton Parish, Renate Albrecht ["Kippy" Kimbrough's girlfriend] visits Williamsburg, Mooreheads get a new house, Eisenhower/Nixon win re-election, Cotesworth Pinckney Lewis becomes new rector of Bruton Parish.
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, January - April 1956., 13 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:13)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, May - August 1956., 15 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:14)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman], wife of George P. Coleman, to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, wife of James Southall Wilson, mainly concerning the activities of their families, September - December 1956., 11 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:15)
  - Letters, 1957., 32 items. (Box-folder 4:16-18)
    Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Folk Art Museum opened, Information Center opened, 350th Jamestown Anniversary, President Eisenhower visits Colonial Williamsburg, Robin Barlowe born, Queen Elizabeth II visits Colonial Williamsburg.
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, January - April 1957., 10 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:16)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, May - July 1957., 11 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:17)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman], wife of George P. Coleman, to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, wife of James Southall Wilson, mainly concerning the activities of their families, August - December 1957., 11 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:18)
  - Letters, 1958., 41 items. (Box-folder 4:19-21)
    Singleton Moorehead in the hospital, visit from Mr. and Mrs. Ezra Pound, Alida Davison has hysterectomy, Lord Botetourt Statue removed from Wren Yard.
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, January - April 1958., 14 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:19)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, May - July 1958., 12 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:20)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman], wife of George P. Coleman, to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, wife of James Southall Wilson, mainly concerning the activities of their families, August - December 1958., 15 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:21)
  - Letters, 1959., 35 items. (Box-folder 4:22-24)
    Mary Coleman gives James Wilson Edgar Allan Poe letters, George Coleman Barlowe born, Isabelle Hubbard [daughter of Jimmie and Blanche Hubbard] marries Sonny Sewell, Doris Kimbrough born.
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, January - April 1959., 13 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:22)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, May - August 1959., 13 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:23)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman], wife of George P. Coleman, to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, wife of James Southall Wilson, mainly concerning the activities of their families, September - December 1959., 9 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 4:24)
  - Letters, 1960., 29 items. (Box-folder 5:1-2)
    Kimbroughs travel to Europe, John D. Rockefeller dies, Kimbroughs move to Atlanta.
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, January - August 1960., 15 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 5:1)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman], wife of George P. Coleman, to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, wife of James Southall Wilson, mainly concerning the activities of their families, September - December 1960., 14 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Letters, 1961., 38 items. (Box-folder 5:3-5)
    Wilsons celebrate 50th wedding anniversary, Isabelle Sewell has a miscarriage, Charles Barlowe born, Dr. Paschall inaugurated as President of the College of William and Mary, Singleton Moorehead has mild stroke.
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, January - March 1961., 11 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 5:3)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, April - August 1961., 14 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 5:4)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman], wife of George P. Coleman, to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, wife of James Southall Wilson, mainly concerning the activities of their families, September - December 1961., 13 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 5:5)
  - Letters, 1962., 28 items. (Box-folder 5:6-7)
    John Glenn's orbit, Mary Coleman decides to donate many of Tucker House books to William and Mary Library, Cynthia Moorehead dies, Eric Kimbrough born, Pamela Sewell born, Duke of Gloucester St. closed to traffic, Eleanor Roosevelt's death.
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, January - May 1962., 14 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 5:6)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman], wife of George P. Coleman, to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, wife of James Southall Wilson, mainly concerning the activities of their families, June - December 1962., 14 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 5:7)
  - Letters, 1963., 40 items. (Box-folder 5:8-10)
    Patricia Drewry marries, James Southall Wilson dies, Singleton Moorehead moves into an apartment, John F. Kennedy assassinated, Scottish relative Susie Bingam visits.
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, January - April 1963., 13 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 5:8)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, May - August 1963., 14 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 5:9)
    - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman], wife of George P. Coleman, to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, wife of James Southall Wilson, mainly concerning the activities of their families, September - December 1963., 13 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 5:10)
  - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman], wife of George P. Coleman, to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, wife of James Southall Wilson, mainly concerning the activities of their families, 1964., 16 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 5:11)
    Susie Bingham returns to Scotland, Mary Coleman announces she "can't get excited over space flights, when I remember what Lindberg and the Wright brothers did 'just the other day,'" Singleton Moorehead dies.
  - Letters, 1965., 29 items. (Box-folder 5:12-13)
    Robert Begg dies, Dr. E.G. Swem dies, Julia Wilson dies.
    - Letters of May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman] to Julia [Tyler] Wilson and to Alida Wilson Davison, January - September 1965., 15 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 5:12)
    - Letters of May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman], wife of George P. Coleman, to Julia [Tyler] Wilson, wife of James Southall Wilson, and Julia Wilson's daughter Alida [Wilson] Davison, mainly concerning the activities of their families, October - December 1965., 14 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 5:13)
  - Letters from May [Mary Haldane Begg Coleman, wife of George P. Coleman, and May's daughter, Janet [Coleman] Kimbrough to Alida [Wilson] Davison, mainly concerning the activities of their families, 1966-1969., 12 items. ALsS. (Box-folder 5:14)
    Janet Kimbrough in hospital for operation on her leg, Mary Coleman in hospital after a fall, [Mary Coleman dies]. Letters date from 1966, including 2 letters - one from 1967 and another from 1969.
  - Christmas verses written and sent by M[ary] H[aldane Begg] C[oleman], 1918-1967., 24 items. C. (Box-folder 5:15)
    Christmas verses written and sent by Mary Coleman annually as Christmas cards to her friends.
  - Stories and poetry written by Mary Haldane Begg Coleman (with one story written by Janet Coleman Kimbrough), 1919, 1948., 4 items. Mss. (Box-folder 5:16)
  - Correspondence concerning two Edgar Allen Poe letters which were initially given to James Southall Wilson by Mary Haldane Begg Coleman, 1959 - 1964., 6 items. ALsS, TDS. (Box-folder 5:17)
  Series 2: Material relating to various subjects
- Material relating to various subjects, 1904-1989. (Box-folder 5:18-21)
  - Material concerning members of the Tucker-Coleman families, 1907 - 1987, bulk 1948 - 1952., 6 items. ALS, NwsCls, PMs. (Box-folder 5:18)
    Includes reminiscences of the Begg family as well as obituaries for a few family members.
  - Material concerning Williamsburg and particularly Colonial Williamsburg, 1928-1989., 14 items. PVs, NwsCls. (Box-folder 5:19)
    Includes articles and obituaries of prominent members of the Williamsburg community.
  - Material relating to the College of William and Mary in Virginia, 1904-1989., 33 items. (Box-folder 5:20-21)
    - Material relating to the College of William and Mary in Virginia, 1904 - 1961., 16 items. PVs, NwsCls. (Box-folder 5:20)
    - Material relating to the College of William and Mary in Virginia, 1961 - 1989., 17 items. PVs, NwsCls. (Box-folder 5:21)
      Includes articles, addresses, and programs of events.
  Series 3: Miscellaneous Materials
- Miscellaneous Materials, 1775-1909, n.d., 16 items. (Box-folder 5:22-25)
  - Letter from Woodrow Wilson, president of Princeton University, to James Southall Wilson turning down an invitation to Williamsburg, March 8, 1909., 1 item. TLS. (Box-folder 5:22)
  - Virginia Pound Notes presented to James Southall Wilson by Alida Jordan Wilson Jones, 1775., 5 items. (Box-folder 5:23)
  - Miscellaneous material which concerns John Tyler, 1961, n.d., 3 items. PMs. (Box-folder 5:24)
  - Miscellaneous materials included in collection. Includes magazines and two recipes, 1961, 1973, 1982, n.d., 7 items. PMs. (Box-folder 5:25)
  Series 4: Photographs
- Photographs of Tyler and Coleman families and friends as well as some photographs of the Tucker House, 1895 - 1964., 27 items. Ps. (Box-folder 5:26)
  - Group photograph, taken at the Jamestown Celebration, subjects include Lyon G. Tyler, Julia G. Tyler, and Charles Coleman, May 13, 1895., 1 item. P1. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 13 1/2"x11" (Box-folder 5:26)
    Taken by Holsinger's Studio of Charlottesville, Virginia.
  - Full view of four women participating in the William and Mary Dramatic Club's "Twelfth Night," 1907., 1 item. P2. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 6 1/2"x8 1/2" (Box-folder 5:26)
    2 women unidentified, Julia G. Tyler (far left) and Elizabeth E. Tyler (far right).
  - Full view of cast of William and Mary Dramatic Club's "Twelfth Night," 1907., 1 item. P3. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 6 1/2"x8 1/2" (Box-folder 5:26)
    All unidentified except Elizabeth E. Tyler (far left) and Julia G. Tyler (3rd from left). 10 subjects total.
  - Head and shoulders, formal portrait of Mary Haldane Begg Coleman, n.d., 1 item. P4. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 6"x8" (Box-folder 5:26)
    Laborie Studio.
  - Full view of George P. Coleman family, n.d., 1 item. P5. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 3 1/2"x5 1/2" (Box-folder 5:26)
    Cynthia Coleman on George P. Coleman's shoulders, Mary Haldane Begg Coleman standing in front of George Coleman and Janet Coleman standing in front of Mary Coleman. Addressed "Love from the whole family to dear Coz Annie."
  - Individuals identified from left to right, Cynthia Coleman, Janet Coleman, and Julia Tyler Wilson sitting in row boat out on the water. Cynthia and Janet Coleman looking at photographer, n.d., 1 item. P6. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 3 1/2"x3 1/2" (Box-folder 5:26)
  - Formal photograph of Janet Coleman and Cynthia Coleman, both girls seated, Janet Coleman on left with long hair and dark bow, Cynthia on right with short hair and white bow, n.d., 1 item. P7. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 4 3/4"x7" (Box-folder 5:26)
    W.W. Foster Studio, Richmond, Virginia.
  - George Coleman seated outside with a black cat on his shoulders, a dog in front of him and a rooster at his side. Labeled "George Coleman and Co.," n.d., 1 item. P8. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 3 1/4"x4 1/4" (Box-folder 5:26)
  - Mary Haldane Begg Coleman in a hat and coat, kneeling outside. She holds a black cat and is playing with a dog, n.d., 1 item. P9. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 3 1/4"x4 1/4" (Box-folder 5:26)
  - Bridesmaids of Janet Coleman's wedding, 1928., 1 item. P10. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 4 1/2"x6 1/2" (Box-folder 5:26)
    7 women in sleeveless dresses, tea length; all holding large bouquets; Cynthia Coleman is in the middle holding bouquet with ribbons. Nancy Wilson is farthest on the right.
  - Full side view of Janet Coleman standing in wedding dress and veil, holding large bouquet with ribbons, 1928., 1 item. P11. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 4 1/2"x6 1/2" (Box-folder 5:26)
  - View of Janet Coleman seated holding baby [Ray "Kippy" Kimbrough, Jr.] with a note "This is my precious baby!..." from Janet, [1930?]., 1 item. P12. Photographic Print mounted on notecard. Ps. black and white Card 3"x5 1/2", print 2"x2 3/4" (Box-folder 5:26)
  - Ray "Kippy" Kimbrough, Jr. standing on tree swing, n.d., 1 item. P13. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 3 1/4"x4 1/4" (Box-folder 5:26)
  - Side view of Cynthia Kimbrough holding a bow and arrow with Ray "Kippy" Kimbrough, Jr. standing behind her, n.d., 1 item. P14. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 2 3/4"x4 1/2" (Box-folder 5:26)
  - Full frontal view of George P. Coleman standing behind Ray "Kippy" Kimbrough, Jr. (holding plastic innertube) and Cynthia Kimbrough, n.d., 1 item. P15. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 2 3/4"x4 1/2" (Box-folder 5:26)
  - Six children outside, the 3 in the foreground sitting and the rest standing, n.d., 1 item. P16. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 2 3/4"x4 1/2" (Box-folder 5:26)
    Labeled on back "Garrets and Colemans." Boy sitting in foreground possibly Ray "Kippy" Kimbrough, Jr. and baby 2nd from left possibly Isabel Hubbard. Other children unidentifiable.
  - Isabel Hubbard (Sr.) sitting on ground and Isabel Hubbard (Jr.) standing in front of her, August 2, 1942., 1 item. P17. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 2 3/4"x4 1/2" (Box-folder 5:26)
  - Full frontal view; from left to right: Ray "Kippy" Kimbrough, Jr., Nikky Dillard, Cynthia Kimbrough, Jimmie Dillard, David Montague, Isabel Hubbard, and Harriet Hodges, 1944., 1 item. P18. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 2 3/4"x4 1/2" (Box-folder 5:26)
  - Full frontal group shot, n.d., 1 item. P19. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 3 1/2"x 5" (Box-folder 5:26)
    George P. Coleman sitting in front of group and Mary Haldane Begg Coleman standing behind him. Others unidentified.
  - Full view of Mary Haldane Begg Coleman sitting at a table reading, 1954., 1 item. P20. Photographic Print. Ps. Color. 3 1/2"x4 1/2" (Box-folder 5:26)
  - Photograph of the portrait of Cynthia Beverley Tucker, 1955., 1 item. P21. Photographic Print. Ps. Color. 3 1/2"x4 1/2" (Box-folder 5:26)
    Attached in notecard with a note written about the portrait by Mary Haldane Begg Coleman.
  - Photograph of the portrait of George P. Coleman, 1964., 1 item. P22. Photographic Print. Ps. Color. 3 1/2"x5" (Box-folder 5:26)
  - Full view of the front of the St. George Tucker House, Williamsburg, Virginia, n.d., 1 item. P23. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 4 1/2"x7" (Box-folder 5:26)
  - Full view of front of the St. George Tucker House, labeled "Tucker House - Williamsburg, Virginia," n.d., 1 item. P24. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 3 1/2"x5 1/2" (Box-folder 5:26)
  - Frontal view of the St. George Tucker House in Williamsburg, Virginia, as seen from the left approach, n.d., 1 item. P25. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 4"x5" (Box-folder 5:26)
  - View of the right side of the front room in the St. George Tucker House, Williamsburg, Virginia, n.d., 1 item. P26. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 4"x5" (Box-folder 5:26)
  - Side view of yard and porch of an unidentified estate, n.d., 1 item. P27. Photographic Print. Ps. Black and White. 7 1/2"x9 1/2" (Box-folder 5:26)
  Series 5: Awards and Medals
- 1904-1946, n.d., 11 items. (Box-folder 5:27-28)
  Artifacts - Princeton University Bicentennial Medal, Harvard Tercentenary Medal, College of William and Mary Alumni Award, Phi Beta Kappa key, Champion of the 14th annual contest of the Virginia State Intercollegiate Oratorical Association, University of Virginia medal, Poe Centenary medal from UVA, William and Mary medal
  - Debate Award from the Philomathean Literary Society of the College of William and Mary awarded to James Southall Wilson, 1902., 1 item. A1. (Box-folder 5:27)
  - Champion medal presented to James Southall Wilson for winning the Fourteenth Annual Contest of the Virginia State Intercollegiate Oratorical Association, May 1904., 1 item. A2. Medal. (Box-folder 5:27)
  - Phi Beta Kappa key presented to James Southall Wilson by William and Mary, n.d., 1 item. A3. Key. (Box-folder 5:27)
  - Medal from the College of William and Mary in Virginia presented to James Southall Wilson, whose initials are engraved on the back of the medal, n.d., 1 item. A4. Medal. (Box-folder 5:27)
  - Philomathean Literary Society of the College of William and Mary pin given to James Southall Wilson, n.d., 1 item. A5. Pin. (Box-folder 5:27)
  - [Edgar Allan] Poe Centenary medal from the University of Virginia presented to James Southall Wilson, 1909., 1 item. A6. Medal. (Box-folder 5:27)
  - University of Virginia medal presented to James Southall Wilson, 1921., 1 item. A7. Medal. (Box-folder 5:27)
  - Alumni Award from the College of William and Mary in Virginia presented to James S[outhall] Wilson [Class of 19]04 "for Service and Loyalty," 1934., 1 item. A8. (Box-folder 5:28)
  - Tercentenary Medal from Harvard University presented to James Southall Wilson, 1936., 1 item. A9. Medal. (Box-folder 5:28)
    Descriptive pamphlet included.
  - Princeton University Bicentennial Medal presented to James Southall Wilson, 1946., 1 item. A10. Medal. (Box-folder 5:28)
  - Kappa Sigma 50[th Anniversary?] pin given to James Southall Wilson, n.d., 1 item. A11. Pin. (Box-folder 5:28)
  Series 6: Scrapbooks
- Scrapbooks, n.d., 3 items. MsV. (Box 6)
  - "Tucker. Collected by Davisons," n.d., 1 item. MsV. (Box 6)
    Scrapbook containing material related to St. George Tucker and his descendants, primarily the Colemans and Kimbroughs
  - "John Tyler Descendants, Vol II, Clippings on the Tylers and Gardiners," n.d., 1 item. MsV. (Box 6)
    Scrapbook containing material and articles related to the descendants of John Tyler, primarily the Wilsons.
  - "Clippings on the Tylers, Vol. I, principally collected from the papers of Julia Gardiner Tyler Wilson and her daughter Alida Wilson Davison," n.d., 1 item. MsV. (Box 6)
    Scrapbook containing miscellaneous material and articles mainly on President John Tyler and his wives Letitia Christian and Julia Gardiner.